indezine.com 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy

About This Privacy Policy  
What Data is Collected?  
What are Cookies, and What is Our Cookie Policy?  
How We Get Data  
How We Use Data?  
How We Share Data?  
Other Information  
Security Issues  
Your Rights  
Policy Concerning Children  
Google Advertising Cookie and Privacy Policies

* * *

The principal activity of this site is to provide rich content to users of software applications. Indezine, the site is part of Indezine.com, and we also run several other sites. All our sites respect your privacy. We exist because of you, and this page explains if we collect, store, use and share data. This Privacy Policy document also looks at your right to access, update, restrict, or remove your personal data.

First of all, we collect little data, and that’s because we want things to be as simple as possible. But yes, some data is collected in case you subscribe to our newsletter (we only collect your name, email address, and country), or through the many partners such as Google, Facebook, Twitter, etc. that make it easier for you to use the content on this site.

In any case, if you have questions, you can always reach out to us via our feedback form.

* * *

## About This Privacy Policy

By using our site, products, or services, you agree to the terms of this privacy policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this privacy policy or any other agreement that governs or relates to your use of the site, products, or services, then you shouldn't use the site, products, or services.

In general, our legal basis for requesting your personal information is consent or purchase so we can deliver valuable information for you to create better presentations, get more design ideas, communicate with us or others, find ways to reach more people, increase your impact, reputation, or standing, and increase your income. Our legitimate purpose is having customers and serving them with this information, and in turn helping them.

Back

* * *

## What Data is Collected?

We may collect personal identification information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our site, subscribe to the newsletter, fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our site. Users indicate visitors, readers, members, or any human interaction. Users do not indicate robotic visits.

Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address. Users may, however, visit our site anonymously without disclosing personal data (excluding their IP address). We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities.

We collect some data from you directly, like when you provide your name and email address to sign up for our newsletter. But some data is also collected automatically, like information about your device, or which areas of our site visitors frequent more than others, or which search engine you used to find us. Here are some specific scenarios:

  * **Customer and Payment Data:** When you buy a product, such as templates or even book consulting time, our third-party software or plug-in collects and stores the data you provide, like your name, email address, and password and in some cases. Of course, you are aware when this happens, because your express permission and intentions are involved at each stage. About payment data, you provide certain payment and billing data directly to our payment processing partners, and this data includes your name, credit card information, payment processor account details, your billing address, and postal code. For security, we do not collect or store sensitive cardholder data, such as full credit card numbers or card authentication data. In fact, we can’t even see it.
  * **Interactions:** If you type in something in a chat window, fill in a feedback form, or even if you attend a webinar, you may type something in input areas. The service we use for such interactions may keep this content, and we may share it anonymously with others.
  * **Payment Data:** When you purchase a product, we collect certain data about your purchase (such as your name and email address) as necessary to process your order.
  * **Giveaways and Surveys:** We often provide giveaways. These may be entirely free to all who take part, or we may choose a winner. We also do surveys to find patterns to determine how users are evolving in their interactions with products, services, or even trends. To make these giveaways or surveys happen, we may use services or third-party platforms. If you do participate, we will collect and store the data you provide as part of participating, such as your name, email address, address, phone number, and any other data. Such data is subject to this Privacy Policy unless otherwise stated in the official rules of the promotion or in another privacy policy. The data collected will be used to administer the giveaway or survey, including for notifying winners and distributing rewards. To receive a reward, you may be required to allow us to post some of your information publicly, like on a winner’s page. Where we use a third-party platform to administer a survey or promotion, the third party’s privacy policy will apply.
  * **Communications and Support:** If you contact us for support, fill in a request on a forum, or report a problem or concern to us directly, or through a third-party service we use, regardless of whether you have created an account with us or the third-party service, we can collect and store your contact information, messages, and other data about you like your name, email address, location, operating system, IP address, and any other data you provide or that we collect through automated means. We use this data to respond to you and research your question or concern, in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If we use third-party support software, that software will store the information. If you comment on a blog post, website page, or anywhere on the site where you can comment, the information you enter is kept and we can use it to reply to you. The information is also used to prevent spammers from making comments.
  * **Affiliates:** We work with many companies that offer us a commission on their products. You may visit their sites via a link on our site or a link on our newsletter, and then purchase something from them. At times, we may get a commission from them. However, in all cases, we are not responsible for the data you provide to them, and you must decide if you want to click on links or buy products from other sources.
  * **Other Services:** If you access or use our services through a third-party platform or service, or click on any third-party links, the collection, use, and sharing of your data will also be subject to the privacy policies and other agreements of that third party. For example, you may access our site through a translation service or even via a proxy. We do not control these services, and in fact you control what you see in this case. Also, our sites contains links to other websites or other information and materials provided by third parties (by way of example, links to third-party social media websites). We do not own or control such other websites or third parties and are not responsible for the information provided at those websites or in such materials. We do not control, and are not responsible for, their privacy policies or the information collected at such third-party websites.
  * **Testimonials:** You may provide us with a testimonial about our services and products. We may, at our discretion, use the testimonial to promote our services. In connection with our use of your testimonial, you hereby agree that we may use your name, voice or likeness, and/or website URL, whatever information you agree to give us, in connection with the testimonial If, at any time, you want us to stop using your testimonial, please contact us via our feedback form, or reply back to any email you received from us and we will cease using the testimonial soon after processing your request. Please note that we often use your testimonials on PowerPoint slides during webinars and may not remember which presentation contains your testimonial, but we will do our best to track them down.
  * **Other Data Collected Automatically:** Other than data collected, as specified earlier on this Privacy Policy page, some more data may be collected via automated processes. This data collection is typical for most server technologies used for hosting, and is collected via server log files and tracking technologies, as detailed in the “What are Cookies, and What is Our Cookie Policy?” and other sections on this page. This data is stored by us and may or may not be associated with your account or your visit patterns. In fact, most of this data is completely anonymous and we get only statistics about our website visitor patterns as a collective figure (Operating system, Computer or device platform, IP address, device identifiers, resolution, browser name, browser language, geography, etc.). Other data may be associated with your account.

Back

* * *

## What are Cookies, and What is Our Cookie Policy?

Cookies are bite-sized like the cookies you may eat, but the differences end there. Cookies are small text files that are stored by your browser, and you can instruct your browser to allow cookies or otherwise.

While our main site doesn’t use such stored cookies, apps from our partners such as Google, Aweber, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, PayPal, Amazon, Disqus, WordPress, Selz, Shareit, and others may use them. Significantly, we only partner with sites that have high-level reputations, and you can find links to privacy policies of these organizations here:

Back

* * *

## How We Get Data

To get data so that we can make this site work better for you, we use cookies, analytical services, and advertisers to compile data. Many of the tools we use offer you the ability to opt out of this data collection.

**Cookies and Data Collection Tools:** Indezine.com and service providers acting on our behalf (such as Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager, and third party advertisers) use server log files and automated data collection tools like cookies, tags, scripts, customized links, device or browser fingerprints, and invisible images (web beacons) when you access and use the Services. These tools automatically track and collect certain System Data and Usage Data when you use the Services. In some cases, we tie data gathered through those tools to other data that we collect as described in this Privacy Policy.

Some third-party services we use, such as our email service and affiliate program, make use of cookies (small files that websites send to your device to uniquely identify your browser or device or to store data in your browser) for things like analyzing your use of the Services, personalizing your experience, making it easier to log into the Services, and recognizing you when you return. We or third-party services use web beacons for things like identifying whether a page was visited, identifying whether an email was opened, and advertising more efficiently by excluding current users from certain promotional messages or identifying the source of a new mobile app download.

You can set your web browser to alert you about attempts to place cookies on your computer, limit the types of cookies you allow, or refuse cookies altogether. If you do, you may not be able to use some or all features of the Services and your experience may be different or less functional.

Some of the third-party partners who provide certain features on our site may also use Local Storage Objects (also known as flash cookies or LSOs) to collect and store data.

Again, see the Cookie Policy on this page.

**Analytics and Online Advertising:** We use third-party browser and mobile analytics services like Google Analytics. These services use Data Collection Tools to help us analyze your use of the Services, including information like the third-party website you arrive from, how often you visit, events within the Services, usage and performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We use this data to improve our Services, better understand how the Services perform on different devices, and understand the results of our promotional efforts. This data is anonymous.

We use third-party advertising services like Facebook, Google’s ad services, and other ad networks and ad servers to deliver advertising about our Services on other websites and applications you use. The ads may be based on things we know about you, like your Usage Data and System Data (as detailed in Section 1), and things that these ad service providers know about you based on their tracking data. The ads can be based on your recent activity or activity over time and across other sites and services, and may be tailored to your interests.

Depending on the types of advertising services we use, they may place cookies or other tracking technologies on your computer, phone, or other devices to collect data about your use of our Services, and may access those tracking technologies in order to serve these tailored advertisements to you.

Back

* * *

## How We Use Data?

We use the data collected in several ways. Here are some example scenarios:

  * To provide our Services
  * To communicate with you, so that we can provide information, resources, and offers via our email newsletter, to respond to your questions and concerns, and to provide information included in products you opt in for or purchase, and also to send you administrative messages about our Services.
  * To troubleshoot issues with offerings provided to you.
  * To secure you against fraud and abuse
  * To improve and update our Services to provide you with a better user experience.
  * To analyze how people use our Services, so that they can be served better.
  * To serve targeted advertising, so that relevant ad content can be shown to visitors.
  * To use, as required by law or necessary for safety and integrity
  * To cater to other scenarios, as we, in our sole discretion, otherwise determine to be necessary to ensure the safety or integrity of our users, employees, third parties, the public, or our Services.

Back

* * *

## How We Share Data?

We could share your data with third parties, but only under compelling circumstances or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy with:

**Service Providers, Contractors, and Agents:** We share your data with third-party companies who perform services on our behalf, like payment processing, data analysis, marketing and advertising services (including retargeted advertising), email and hosting services, and customer services and support. These service providers may access your personal data and are required to use it solely as we direct, to provide our requested service.

**To Power Social Media Features:** The social media features in the Services (like a Facebook button) may allow the third-party social media provider to collect things like your IP address and which page of the Services you’re visiting, and to set a cookie to enable the feature. Your interactions with these features are governed by the third-party company’s privacy policy.

**For Security and Legal Compliance:** We may disclose your data to third parties if we (in our sole discretion) have a good faith belief that the disclosure is:

  * Permitted or required by law;
  * Requested as part of a judicial, governmental, or legal inquiry, order, or proceeding;
  * Reasonably necessary as part of a valid subpoena, warrant, or other legally-valid request;
  * Reasonably necessary to enforce our Terms of Use, Privacy Policy, and other legal agreements;
  * Required to detect, prevent, or address fraud, abuse, misuse, potential violations of law (or rule or regulation), or security or technical issues; or
  * Reasonably necessary in our discretion to protect against imminent harm to the rights, property, or safety of our entity, our users, employees, members of the public, or our Services.
  * We may also disclose data about you to our auditors and legal advisors in order to assess our disclosure obligations and rights under this Privacy Policy.

**During a Change in Control:** If our entity undergoes a business transaction like a merger, acquisition, corporate divestiture, or dissolution (including bankruptcy), or a sale of all or some of its assets, we may share, disclose, or transfer all of your data to the successor organization during such transition or in contemplation of a transition (including during due diligence).

**After Aggregation/De-identification:** We can disclose or use aggregate or de-identified data for any purpose.

**With Your Permission:** With your consent, we may share data to third parties outside the scope of this Privacy Policy.

Back

* * *

## Other Information

This site does not enable visitors to communicate with other visitors (excluding links to external sites) or to post information to be accessed by others. Such external sites may collect personal data about their visitors.

This site links to other sites on the Internet. Content and privacy policies of those sites are the responsibility of their respective owners.

Most advertisements on this site are provided by outside advertisement companies and may contain cookies. These cookies are collected by their respective companies and are not accessible to Indezine.com.

If you subscribe to the mailing list for this site, rest assured that no subscriber information is ever provided to anyone else for any other use.

If you have questions or feel that we have not handled information about you properly, you may contact us through the feedback form on this site.

Back

* * *

## Security Issues

We take security measures very seriously, so as to prevent you from any unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or deletion of the data collected and stored. All these measures may differ, depending upon the type and sensitivity of the data. Having said so, no system can ever be guaranteed to be entirely secure, so we cannot guarantee uninterrupted communication between you and us, the services, or any information provided to us in connection with the data we collect through the services will be free from unauthorized access by third parties.

Further, we do not control policies and procedures of third-party organizations and partners whom we work with, although we do make every possible effort to choose organizations and partners with strong security and privacy policies. In fact, we have linked to privacy policies of many such organizations and partners previously on this page.

Back

* * *

## Your Rights

You possess rights that relate to the use of your data, and this includes your ability to opt out of promotional emails, cookies, and collection of your data by certain analytics providers. To do so, you can update or terminate your account from within our Services, and you can also contact us for individual rights requests about your personal data.

**Your Choices About Data:** You can decide not to provide certain data, but if you do so, you may be unable to use certain features of our Services.

  * To stop receiving newsletter emails from us, you can opt out by using the Unsubscribe link in the email you receive. Note that regardless of your email preference settings, we will send you transactional and relationship messages regarding the Services, including administrative confirmations, order confirmations, product content that is “dripped” out over time, important updates about the Services, and notices about our policies.
  * control whether location or other data is collected and shared.
  * To get information and control cookies used for tailored advertising from participating companies, see the consumer opt-out pages for the [ Network Advertising Initiative](http://llink.to/?u=http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices&e=a19c8627dbc04d23b48f81af41850656) and [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://llink.to/?u=http://www.aboutads.info/choices/&e=a19c8627dbc04d23b48f81af41850656), or if you’re located in the European Union, visit the [Your Online Choices](http://llink.to/?u=http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/&e=a19c8627dbc04d23b48f81af41850656)
  * The browser or device you use may allow you to control cookies and other types of local data storage. Your wireless device may also allow you to site. To opt out of Google’s display advertising or customize Google Display Network ads, visit the [Google Ads Settings page](http://llink.to/?u=https://www.google.com/settings/ads&e=a19c8627dbc04d23b48f81af41850656).
  * To opt out of allowing Google Analytics to use your data for analytics or enrichment, see the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](http://llink.to/?u=https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout&e=a19c8627dbc04d23b48f81af41850656).

If you have any questions about your data, our use of it, or your rights, [please contact us via our feedback form](http://llink.to/?u=https://www.indezine.com/feedback.html&e=a19c8627dbc04d23b48f81af41850656).

**Accessing, Updating, and Deleting Your Personal Data:** To request to access, correct, or delete your personal data, please contact us via our feedback form. For your protection and to locate your data, we may require you provide the email address associated with your account. It will further help us to find your records if you tell us which product, download, and newsletter you are receiving. We may need to verify your identity before implementing your request.

Please note that we retain certain data where we have a lawful basis to do so, including for mandatory record-keeping and to complete transactions.

Please note: Even after your account is terminated, some or all of your data may still be visible to others, including without limitation any data that has been

  * Copied, stored, or disseminated by other users (including product content);
  * Shared or disseminated by you or others (including in your shared content); or 
  * Posted to a third-party platform (such as social media).

Even after your account is terminated, we retain your data for as long as we have a legitimate purpose to do so (and in accordance with applicable law), including to assist with legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We may retain and disclose such data pursuant to this Privacy Policy after your account has been terminated.

To read a brief description related to our GDPR compliance, visit the Indezine GDPR Compliance page.

Back

* * *

## Policy Concerning Children

We respect and recognize privacy interests related to children, and encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. Children under 13 (or under 16 in the European Economic Area) should not use our Services. If we learn that we’ve collected personal data from a child under those ages, we will take reasonable steps to delete it. 

Parents or guardians who believe that we may have collected personal data from a child under those ages, please contact us via our feedback form to submit a request for removal.

Back

* * *

## Google Advertising Cookie and Privacy Policies

In March 2009, Google (one of the advertisers on this site) announced that they would be making some changes -- and that the following info in our privacy policy needs to be thus stated:

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on your site.
  * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

Back
